<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Blog on Some Interesting Things</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Blog on Some Interesting Things</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 25 May 2025 20:24:03 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Baladys_anomaly</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/baladys_anomaly/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 May 2025 20:24:03 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/baladys_anomaly/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Parikhs Theorem</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/parikhs-theorem/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 May 2025 20:23:31 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/parikhs-theorem/</guid>
      <description>Don&amp;rsquo;t let the lobbyists at big PDA have you thinking there&amp;rsquo;s only one way to prove a language is context free. Parikh&amp;rsquo;s theorem is a helpful alternative when a pda seems too complex to draw. In this post we&amp;rsquo;ll go over Parikh&amp;rsquo;s Theorem, its proof, and how to use it. Strap in because it&amp;rsquo;s gonna be a wild ride.&#xA;Background Like any good TCS concept, Parikh&amp;rsquo;s Theorem starts with a slightly intimidating amount of definitions.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ogdens_theorem</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/ogdens_theorem/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 May 2025 20:23:22 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/ogdens_theorem/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Beginners Guide to the Learning With Errors Problem</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/a-beginners-guide-to-the-learning-with-errors-problem/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Mar 2025 16:36:09 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/a-beginners-guide-to-the-learning-with-errors-problem/</guid>
      <description>Learning Learning with Errors with Errors Why am I writing this&#xA;my experience learning was a hodgepodge of blog posts, lecture notes, and research papers, all of which assume varying degrees of previous knowledge. Create a central starting point for someone interested in LWE/crypto with the only assumption being a reasonable intuition about lattices Provide code as well as some short proof ideas Also more resources to go in depth about a topic Why LWE FHE Quantum Resistant Public key generation The Basics key, vector, packed message, noise Go over generation Modulus Switching Key Switching Security Guaranty Variants </description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
