<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Blog on Some Interesting Things</title>
    <link>https://johnbntn.github.io/blog/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Blog on Some Interesting Things</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 03 Aug 2025 09:47:53 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://johnbntn.github.io/blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Hacking a Pass Together in LLVM`s OCaml Bindings</title>
      <link>https://johnbntn.github.io/hacking-a-pass-together-in-llvms-ocaml-bindings/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Aug 2025 09:47:53 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://johnbntn.github.io/hacking-a-pass-together-in-llvms-ocaml-bindings/</guid>
      <description>If you&amp;rsquo;re writing a production quality compiler, it&amp;rsquo;s no longer good enough to just have correct code, you need speed. Compiler optimizations have become an incredibly important aspect of modern compiler design and will only grow in importance as languages are developed for increasingly specialized, computation heavy domains.&#xA;What is LLVM? LLVM (which doesn&amp;rsquo;t stand for anything) is a codegen and optimization engine. It stands out for being architecture independent, so you can write optimizations in LLVM&amp;rsquo;s IR and let LLVM handle generating code for specific architectures.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ogden&#39;s Theorem and Inherent Ambiguity</title>
      <link>https://johnbntn.github.io/ogdens-theorem-and-inherent-ambiguity/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Apr 2025 20:23:22 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://johnbntn.github.io/ogdens-theorem-and-inherent-ambiguity/</guid>
      <description>The pumping lemma for context free languages is a useful tool to prove a language to be non context free. But sometimes proofs about CFLs require more powerful tools. William Ogden, during his PhD at Stanford, published a paper that describes a way to generalize a the pumping lemma, allowing you to, in a sense, &amp;ldquo;choose where to pump&amp;rdquo;.&#xA;But why study it? Well, most notably, the theorem lends itself well to a proof about the inherent ambiguity of CFLs; less notably, I think it&amp;rsquo;s cool.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
